<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>api on COBADID</title>
    <link>/tags/api/</link>
    <description>Recent content in api on COBADID</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>BlueGreen Labs for COBADID &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/tags/api/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>COBADID launch</title>
      <link>/post/cobadid-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cobadid-launch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Belgian research institutes hold a vast amount of scientific data pertaining to the Congo Basin. Recovered data are currently used within among others the fields of forestry, agronomy, climatology, ecology, botany &amp;amp; remote sensing. Currently, Congo Basin tropical rainforests continue to provide an important negative feedback on the global carbon cycle (0.34Pg C yr-1)&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. At the same time, Congo Basin forests support the local economy (~3-6% of the gross domestic product), while the forest’s existence is equally threatened by the search for food security and associated intensifying agriculture. At this interface between ecological, sociological and economical factors sits a need for accurate, findable, accessible, linked and/or integrated data to inform forest management, carbon cycle and climatological modelling, and state of the art reprocessing of (digitized) historical data to achieve UN sustainable development goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past decade several BELSPO projects have supported the progressive digitization of key data from these analogue archives across a wide range of research disciplines. In this context the archives of the Institut National d’Etudes Agronomique du Congo Belge (INEAC) at the State Archives, the Royal Museum for Central Africa (RMCA) and the historical African herbarium collection of the Botanic Garden Meise (BGM), are key. These analogue data included both physical samples, such as herbarium specimens, or wood collections, but also, paper records of climatology, valuable grey literature and aerial photographs. Recent field work resulted in additional data on forest dynamics that are complementary to archived information. Digitization of these data, and their derived measurements (e.g. chemical and structural variables) has enabled the production of innovative contemporary research, underlining the relevance of Belgian research institutes and its scientists in an international setting &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the XYLAREDD&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; project allowed the verification of the botanical authenticity of xylarium samples and upgraded the quality of image material and derived data such as wood density. The HERBAXYLAREDD&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; project focussed on common traits between the xylarium specimens and information on foliar, reproductive and phenological traits of African herbarium samples and their geographic distribution patterns. Exploring the State Archives and the RMCA collections the COBECORE&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; project digitized and transcribed historical climate data, grey literature on agronomy and forestry research, as well as aerial remote sensing data across the central Congo Basin. In short, digital collections on Congo Basin data have not only proven to be vast, but also diverse and versatile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;global-objectives&#34;&gt;Global Objectives&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we propose to link and integrate digital heritage collections centered around past century INEAC research efforts, making these data both findable, accessible and easier to valorize within both a scientific, policy or educational context and eventually contribute to achieving the UN  sustainable development goals. We therefore aim to develop Application programming interface (API) to existing databases as one of the main end-products of this project. In addition, we foresee the generation of linked domain specific datasets for machine learning and dedicated studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;methodology&#34;&gt;Methodology&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The COBADID project will bring together the expertise of 5 partners overseeing large digital collections, and their derived products, in a 4-year project to link these historical datasets while guaranteeing both data quality and covering various needs within the larger research communities. Our objectives follow a tiered structure, delivering both data and infrastructure solutions with multiple tangible deliverables, and allows for asynchronous work schedules to maximizing project efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lewis et al. 2009 Nature &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hubau et al. 2020 Nature &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kearsley et al. 2013 Nature Comm. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hubau et al. 2019 Nature Plants &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valorisation of the Tervuren xylarium for rainforest ecology &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interdisciplinary exploitation of the Federal Herbarium and Xylarium for tropical forest management &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congo basin eco-climatological data recovery and valorisation. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
