<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors on COBADID</title>
    <link>/authors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authors on COBADID</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>BlueGreen Labs for COBADID &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Hans Beeckman holds a PhD on the numerical analysis of tree-ring data. He is senior scientist and curator of the Xylarium at the Royal Museum for Central Africa and head of the Wood Biology Service. The xylarium is the largest wood collection of tropical African species outside of DR Congo and forms the source of data on wood traits stored in the Inside Wood database. Dr. Beeckman also curates the Tervuren Wood database, cataloging these samples. The Service studies the material wood as part of living beings. This includes the analysis of cells and tissues (wood anatomy) and the growth of trees with  most focus on the rainforests of Central Africa. His current research includes studies of the dynamics of cambial activity, the climate information in growth-ring patterns and the variability of wood traits. Furthermore, he addresses scientific questions on forest history (species diversity) and archaeobotany are addressed through analysis of charcoal containing layers in the soil (pedoanthracology). Through courses and identification services he has extensive contacts with the timber industries which will assist in dissemination of the data within the context of sustainable forest management.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/corneille/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/corneille/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Ewango holds a doctoral degree from the University of Wageningen. His work focussed on the ecology of lianas in DR Congo and tropical tree biodiversity. He was responsible for the Okapi Faunal Reserve&amp;rsquo;s botany program in the Democratic Republic of Congo from 1996 to 2003. For his conservation efforts he received numerous awards, among others the Future of Nature Award (2011) and the Goldman Environmental Prize (2005). Furthermore, his work was instrumental to the creation of the Flore d’Afrique Centrale, as proposed to be made accessible by API in COBADID.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/jan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/jan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Prof. dr. Jan Van den Bulcke obtained a MSc degree in Bioscience Engineering (Land and Forest management) and a MSc degree in Environmental Sanitation at the Ghent University in 2000 and 2001 respectively. He obtained his PhD in 2006 and is since 2016 tenure track professor at the Laboratory of Wood Technology (UGent-Woodlab) in the research domain of sustainable primary production. His main research interest is  the climate – xylem growth relation at multiple temporal and spatial scales. He is and has been involved in several research projects dealing with imaging and analysis of wood and tree growth of which the TOCOWO (BRAIN B2/191/P2/TOCOWO, 2020-2022) project and the Afrormosia (UGent BOF-DOS, Chadrack Kafuti, 2019-2022) PhD project are most related to this proposal.  He has a pioneering role in the ongoing development of a (globally) unique X-ray CT-based tool-chain for the analysis of increment cores and micro-cores of trees, is member of the board of UGCT, a centre of expertise for CT scanning at UGent, and has a longstanding collaboration with the RMCA on tree performance studies in the tropics. He is member of the Scientific Committee of IRG and member of ATR.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/michael/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/michael/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As head of the Service “Contemporary Archives” at the National Archives of Belgium (NAB1) since 2011, Dr. Michaël Amara is well acquainted with the historical relevance and the conservation of archives of all types. One of his main tasks concerns the conservation and valorization of archives. More than 24 million images are available on the websites of the State Archives. He was involved in many projects of digitalization. He’s a specialist in First World War Studies and obtained his PhD from the University of Brussels [ULB] (Dep. of Contemporary History) (2007) with a thesis on Belgian refugees in France, Netherlands and UK during the First World War.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/sofie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/sofie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Sofie Meeus holds a PhD in evolutionary biology from the University of Leuven (KU Leuven). After obtaining her PhD in 2014 she continued her research career at Stirling University (UK) as a PLANT FELLOW (Marie Curie COFUND programme) postdoctoral researcher studying polyploidization as a speciation mechanism. Since 2017, she has been working as a research scientist and coordinator of the COBECORE project at Meise Botanic Garden. During the course of this project she worked intensively with the African herbarium collection at MeiseBG, developed a full workflow for digitizing leaf functional traits including automatic detection of leaf structures using artificial intelligence and made the link with STEM education through the KIKS project that won the Queen Paola Award for Education 2020 (NL: Koningin Paolaprijs voor het onderwijs).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
